1. [ETS](https://www.ets.org/content/ets-org/language-master/en/home.html) 
2. [Legal Home](https://www.ets.org/content/ets-org/language-master/en/home/legal/home.html) 
3. Privacy and Security 

1. [Go Back](javascript:history.back())

Privacy and Security
====================

* * *

ETS recognizes the importance of protecting your privacy. This Privacy Notice describes our practices related to personal information privacy and security.

ETS has a global privacy program to protect all "Personal Information." Personal Information is any information that we can use to identify you (such as your name, username or identification number) or contact you (such as your email address or telephone number). Personal Information includes other types of information (such as test scores or demographic data) when that information is associated with your Personal Information.

Privacy Notice
--------------

This Privacy Notice describes our practices with respect to Personal Information we collect via ETS websites, platforms and applications that collect Personal Information from you. It also describes our practices with respect to Personal Information collected in other ways, such as when you register for and take ETS tests, or when we receive information from a school or test center administrator. If you are a test taker, additional information about privacy and security is included in many of the ETS Test Bulletins.

By using an ETS platform or otherwise providing us with Personal Information, you agree to our privacy terms. You can contact us at any time with questions or concerns about privacy by sending an email to [**etsinfo@ets.org**](mailto:etsinfo@ets.org) or by writing to us at the addresses in the Contact section below.

Please note that this Privacy Notice applies to all Personal Information collected by ETS via its online test registrations system. Our distributors and agents may provide vouchers to facilitate test registration, but test candidates must provide their data to ETS to register for and take tests. We will use and protect all test taker data in accordance with this Privacy Notice. 

Within this Privacy Notice, you will find information about:

### Children

ETS is committed to handling children’s data appropriately and in compliance with applicable laws.

* Our websites and test registration platforms are not designed for children under 16, and ETS does not knowingly collect Personal Information directly from children under the age of 16 on these sites. Parents and schools may create accounts for children, such as registering them for tests. The parent or school (acting for the parent) must consent to our processing of the child’s data as described in this Privacy Notice for ETS to administer the test.  
    We encourage parents and teachers to spend time online with children and to monitor their online activities. If you believe that a child has created an account on our website without having proper parental consent, please contact us to have the account deactivated by sending us an email at [**etsinfo@ets.org**](mailto:etsinfo@ets.org) or by calling us at **1-609-921-9000**.
* ETS provides parents and teachers with the ability to download certain apps that they and their children or students can use for educational purposes, such as to improve reading fluency. Some of these apps are intended for use by children under 13. ETS may collect the child's first name or nickname, age or grade in school, and basic demographic data from the parent or guardian when the child’s account is created. When the child uses the app, ETS collects audio recordings of the child's voice when the child reads passages (or a transcript of the recording), the child's responses to questions that test skills such as reading comprehension and other data relating to the child's use of the app, such as how long the child spends using the app. Our apps do not collect any other Personal Information from children, and they do not use cookies or other data-collection technologies.  
    ETS anonymizes the information collected by its educational apps and uses the information for research purposes. ETS does not maintain identifiable data about children, and children cannot make their own data publicly available via the apps. ETS does not (and will not permit any third party to) associate identifying information with research data.  
    Parents and teachers can review and delete the child's information at any time in the app. Parents and teachers can restrict ETS' collection of additional information at any time by deleting the app. Parents or teachers who have questions about how ETS handles children's data may contact ETS by sending us an email at [**etsinfo@ets.org**](mailto:etsinfo@ets.org) or by calling us at **1-609-921-9000**.

### Categories, Sources and Purposes for Collecting Personal Information

The chart below describes the categories of personal information we collect, the sources of that information, the reasons we collect it, and the types of people to whom we may disclose the information. Please note that we may use and disclose any personal information for our “Everyday Business Purposes”\* as permitted by law. We may disclose any personal information to our affiliates and to the service providers and contractors that need to use the information to provide services to us. We have contracts with these companies that require them to protect our information and to comply with law. We may also use and disclose any information when required by law, such as to law enforcement agencies or in connection with litigation, or with your consent.

| Contact Information |     |
| --- | --- |
| Representative Data Elements | * You name, previous names and preferred names<br>* Business or residential mailing address<br>* Email address<br>* Work, home or mobile telephone numbers |
| Sources | We collect this information from individuals, such as when they sign up for emails or register for tests. We collect this information about professionals from services that provide sales leads and publicly available sources, such as LinkedIn. |
| Additional Purposes for Collecting | We use contact information to identify you and communicate with you. Contact information is also used to personalize our communications, such as by using your preferred name. |
| Additional Categories of Recipients | We disclose contact information to our service providers, contractors and others, such as couriers and telecommunications providers who delivery our communications. |
| Government-issued Identification Numbers |     |
| Representative Data Elements | * Social security number in the US or national ID number outside the US<br>* Tax ID number |
| Sources | We collect this information from you. |
| Purposes for Collecting | We use this type of information for identity verification and legal compliance, such as reporting payments made to suppliers as required by law. |
| Categories of Recipients | We disclose this information to service providers and contractors and others, such as payment processors, auditors and government agencies. |
| Other Unique Identifiers |     |
| Representative Data Elements | * System identifiers (e.g., usernames or online credentials)<br>* Device identifiers<br>* Advertising identifiers |
| Sources | We may assign a unique identification number to you when you become a customer or a supplier. We collect device identifiers and other unique identifiers from your devices and from our websites, apps and platforms, which use cookies and other data collection technologies. |
| Purposes for Collecting | We use unique identifiers to identify you or your device, including to associate you with different devices that you may use, for internal record-keeping and reporting, including for data matching and analytics, and to track your interactions with us, including for ad delivery and personalization. |
| Categories of Recipients | We disclose these identifiers to our service providers, contractors and others, such as entities that assist with our information technology programs (such as website hosting companies) or administer promotions. We may also disclose these identifiers to auditors and companies that assist with security and fraud prevention. Advertising identifiers are shared with third parties as part of our online advertising programs. |
| Biometric Identifiers |     |
| Representative Data Elements | * Fingerprint, voice print, or physical or behavioral characteristics used for identity verification or authentication<br>* Mathematical representation of your biometric identifier, such as the template maintained for comparison |
| Sources | We collect this information from you when you take an ETS test. |
| Purposes for Collecting | Where permitted by law, ETS uses biometric identifiers to identify and authenticate test takers and test center administrators. ETS collects digital photographs and digital voice recordings, and coverts these samples into mathematical representations called templates, which can be compared to the templates previously collected by ETS and to templates created from your government-issued identification documents.<br><br>ETS also collects behavioral biometrics for test security in connection with online tests. For example, when you complete written portions of an online test, we may analyze keystroke patterns and other behavioral characteristics to help verify your identity and authenticate you based on these patterns. <br><br>ETS uses biometric identifiers solely to support test security and integrity and for related purposes (such prosecution of fraud or intellectual property theft). |
| Categories of Recipients | We may disclose biometric identifiers to our service providers, contractors and others, such as cybersecurity firms, law firms or government agencies, if we detect misconduct. |
| Additional Information | Our [Biometric Information Privacy Policy](https://www.ets.org/content/ets-org/language-master/en/home/legal/privacy/biometric-information.html) provides additional information about our use of biometric identifiers. |
| Relationship Information |     |
| Representative Data Elements | We collect relationship information to help us do business with you and to support [ETS Research](https://www.ets.org/content/ets-org/language-master/en/home/research.html). For example:<br><br>* For test takers, we collect the types of tests that you want to take, your school affiliation, expected degree and graduation date, and similar information to help us offer you personalized content as well as demographic data, such as language(s) spoken, which helps support ETS Research.<br>* For professionals, we collect your credentials and affiliations and the products and services that may interest you or your school.<br>* For test center administrators, this may include information about your relationship with your test center and the tests you administer.<br><br>Platforms such as GradSchoolMatch or GRE Search Service, may collect additional relationship information to help match students with educational programs, fellowships, scholarships and similar offerings. |
| Sources | We collect this type of information from you and from other sources, such as publicly available information about you from social media platforms. We may collect additional information from partners or by inferring information about you based on your past interactions with us or our partners. |
| Purposes for Collecting | We use this type of information to better understand you and to understand our customers generally, to design products, services and programs that appeal to our customers, to identify prospective customers and for internal business purposes, such as marketing, quality control, training and analytics. |
| Categories of Recipients | We disclose this information to our service providers and contractors. We disclose this information to other entities with your consent, such as when you direct us to send score reports or if you enroll in a Search Service.<br><br>While we do not sell consumer information for monetary consideration, your information may be also be shared as permitted by law, such as with third parties as part of our online advertising programs. |
| Transaction Information |     |
| Representative Data Elements | Transaction information includes all customer and supplier account information, qualification data, purchase history and related records, such as:<br><br>* Test registration records, test administration records, order information about your use of our content (such as if you access your scores online, use test prep material or complete surveys), customer or test center administrator account information (such as if you email us for support) and payment card information as needed to process your payments<br>* Records related to downloads and use of our websites and apps<br>* Records related to financial, health or religious accommodation requests <br>* Customer service records<br>* Logs, such as visitor logs, server logs, and similar records |
| Sources | We collect this type of information from you and from our service providers and contractors and from other companies, such as our payment processors, test center administrators, resellers or agents. <br><br>We may collect this information automatically when you visit our facilities our use our websites or apps. For example, our apps automatically log access requests, downloads and other transactions. |
| Purposes for Collecting | We use this type of information to fulfill our business relationship with you and/or your company, including administering tests, for customer service, recordkeeping, compliance, and dispute resolution. We also use this information for our internal business purposes, such as research, finance, quality control, training, reporting and analytics, and for risk management, fraud prevention and similar purposes. |
| Additional Categories of Recipients | We disclose transaction information to our service providers, contractors and others, such as to other entities as needed to complete the transaction, including unaffiliated test center administrators, and to our auditors, financial institutions, and government agencies. If you are a professional, we may disclose this information to the institution that employs you. We disclose this information to other entities with your consent, such as when you direct us to send score reports or if you enroll in a Search Service. |
| Financial information |     |
| Representative Data Elements | * Bank account number and details<br>* Payment card information<br><br>If you request a fee waiver, fee reduction or scholarship, we may collect additional about your financial situation. |
| Sources | We collect this type of information from you and from our service providers, financial institutions and payment processors. |
| Purposes for Collecting | We use financial information to fulfill our business relationship with you, such as processing payments, issuing refunds and collections, and for internal business purposes, such as finance functions, audits, fraud prevention and compliance. |
| Categories of Recipients | We disclose financial information to our service providers, contractors and others, such as payment processors, financial institutions, auditors and government agencies. |
| Health Information |     |
| Representative Data Elements | * Information needed to accommodate disabilities<br>* Information about workplace accidents and occupational safety |
| Sources | We collect health information from you if you need assistance testing or accessing our products, services or facilities. We may collect this heath information from you and from others in connection with a workplace accident. |
| Purposes for Collecting | We use health data to accommodate disabilities and enable accessibility of our products, services and facilities, and for occupational health and safety programs and other internal business purposes, such as risk management and compliance. |
| Categories of Recipients | We disclose health information to our service providers, contractors and others, such as healthcare providers, insurers, first responders (in the event of an emergency), or government agencies. We may also disclose health information to others if needed to provide you with an accommodation. |
| Additional Information | Please read the ETS [Consumer Health Data Privacy Policy](https://www.ets.org/content/ets-org/language-master/en/home/legal/privacy/consumer-health-data-privacy-policy.html) for information about how we handle “consumer health data” subject to the Washington My Health My Data Act. |
| Online & Technical Information  <br>_Please read our statement about Cookies & Other Data Collection Technologies for additional information._ |     |
| Representative Data Elements | * IP address<br>* Device information and identifiers<br>* System and server logs, including access logs <br>* Data from cookies, pixel tags or other online tools |
| Sources | We collect this type of information from your computer or devices when you interact with our platforms, websites and applications. For example, when you visit our websites, our server logs record your IP address and other information. We may also receive this information from third parties, including computer security services and advertising partners. |
| Additional Purposes for Collecting | We use technical information for system administration, technology management, including optimizing our websites and applications, and for information security and cybersecurity purposes, including detecting threats to our networks and systems. <br><br>If you take online tests, we use the information for test integrity purposes, including to detect cheating or other misconduct.<br><br>We also use online and technical information for personalization, to better understand our customers and prospective customers and to enhance our relationship information, including by associating you with different devices and browsers, and for online targeting and advertising purposes. |
| Additional Categories of Recipients | We may disclose this type of information to our service providers and contractors, and others such as companies that support our information technology and cybersecurity programs. Online and Technical Information may be shared with third parties as part of our online advertising programs. |
| Audio Visual Information |     |
| Representative Data Elements | * Photograph<br>* Audio and video records captured during testing<br>* Videoconference records, CCTV recordings<br>* Call center recordings and call monitoring records<br>* Voicemails |
| Sources | We collect this type of information from you. We may also collect this information automatically, such as when we record calls to our call center and use CCTV cameras in our facilities. |
| Additional Purposes for Collecting | We use this type of information as needed to provide our tests and for other internal business purposes, such as call recordings used for training, quality control, and compliance and for research. We also use these data for security purposes and loss prevention. |
| Categories of Recipients | We may disclose this type of information to our service providers and contractors that support our information technology, security, and loss prevention programs. |
| Inferred and Derived Information |     |
| Representative Data Elements | * Propensities and attributes generated by internal analytics programs |
| Sources | We create inferred and derived data elements by analyzing other data, such as our relationship and transactional information. |
| Additional Purposes for Collecting | We combine inferred data with other relationship information and use this type of information to better understand you and to understand our customers generally, to identify prospective customers and for internal business purposes, such as research, test security, quality control, training and analytics. |
| Categories of Recipients | We disclose derived information to our service providers, contractors and others, such as management consulting firms and security firms. |
| Compliance Data |     |
| Representative Data Elements | * “Know your customer” records<br>* Occupational and environmental safety records<br>* Intellectual property protection program records<br>* Records relating to complaints and internal investigations<br>* Records related to the exercise of privacy rights<br>* Records related to security incidents, including notifications |
| Sources | We collect compliance data from you and from our providers, contractors, and others, such as screening companies service, investigators, legal advisors and government agencies. We may generate compliance records internally, such as when we document a workplace event. |
| Purposes for Collecting | We use compliance data for internal governance, corporate ethics programs, institutional risk management, reporting, demonstrating compliance and accountability externally, and as needed for litigation and defense of claims. |
| Categories of Recipients | We disclose compliance to our service providers, contractors and others, such as auditors, investigators, lawyers, advisors, government agencies and others as required by law. |

| \* Everyday Business Purposes encompasses the business purposes for which any personal information may processed: |
| --- |
| * To provide the information, product or service requested by the individual or as reasonably expected given the context in which with the personal information was collected (such as providing customer service and preference management, providing product updates and dispute resolution)<br>* For identity and credential management, including identity verification and authentication, system and technology administration<br>* To protect the security and integrity of ETS’ tests, systems, networks, applications and data, including detecting, analyzing and resolving security threats, and collaborating with cybersecurity centers, consortia and law enforcement about imminent threats<br>* For fraud detection and prevention,<br>* For legal and regulatory compliance, including all uses and disclosures of personal information that are required by law or for reasonably needed for compliance with company policies and procedures, such as: anti-money laundering programs, security and incident response programs, intellectual property protection and anti-piracy programs, and our ethics and compliance hotlines,<br>* For corporate audit, analysis and reporting,<br>* To enforce our contracts and to protect against injury, theft, legal liability, fraud or abuse, to protect people or property, including physical security programs<br>* To de-identify the data or create aggregated datasets, such as for consolidating reporting, research or analytics,<br>* To make back-up copies for business continuity and disaster recovery purposes, and<br>* For corporate governance, including mergers, acquisitions and divestitures. |

### Use of Information by ETS Research

ETS uses personal information for various research initiatives. For example, ETS may consider how certain types of test takers (such as nonnative English speakers) respond to specific test questions. Similarly, our educational apps collect data to help ETS understand and improve reading skills. ETS' research initiatives reflect our commitment to fairness and equity in testing, helping to ensure that our tests are accessible and free from bias. They also seek to improve teaching, learning and assessment.

The personal information used for research is not used in an identifiable manner. When possible, ETS anonymizes or pseudonymizes its research data, and ETS may process Personal Information as needed to create de-identified datasets for research. ETS will not (and will not permit any third party to) associate individually identifying information with research data. Our research results do not contain any identifiable data, and research data are not used to target or profile individuals.

Learn more about [**ETS Research**](https://www.ets.org/content/ets-org/language-master/en/home/research.html).

### Your Privacy Rights and Choices

ETS respects your rights to access, correct and request erasure or restriction of your personal data as required by law. Depending on where you live, these rights may include:

* The right to be informed about our collection, use and disclosure of your personal information,
* The right to know if we maintain your personal information, and if we do, to access that information (subject to the rights of others) and to request that we provide your information in a portable format,
* The right to ask us to correct your information if it is incomplete or incorrect,
* The right to ask that we delete your personal information, and
* The right to object to our processing of your personal information, including the rights to object to:
    * the sale of your personal information,
    * the sharing or use of your personal information for certain types of online targeted advertising,
    * the use of profiling or automated decision-making which might significantly affect you and,
    * if we are processing your personal information based on your consent, to withdraw your consent at any time.

Please understand that these rights are subject to some limitations. For example, we may require documentation to support certain corrections to your information, and we generally cannot restrict or delete personal information in those situations where our retention is required for our internal business purposes or to comply with law.

We will not retaliate against you if you exercise your privacy rights.

To exercise your privacy rights, please follow these steps:

* **OPT-OUT OF ONLINE ADVERTISING:** ETS does not sell your personal information for monetary consideration. We may share your personal information in connection with online advertising programs. To opt-out of sharing in connection with online targeting: Cookie Management Platform
* **OPT-OUT OF MARKETING COMMUNICATIONS.** You have the right to opt-out of our marketing and commercial communications. To exercise this right:
    * To opt-out of emails, click the link labeled “unsubscribe” at the bottom of any email we send you.
    * To revoke permissions that you may have given to send text messages, text STOP in response to any message.

If you have more than one email address or if you have changed your email address, please email [**etsinfo@ets.org**](mailto:etsinfo@ets.org) for assistance with changing your marketing preferences. Also, please note that even if you opt-out of commercial emails, we may still need to contact you with important transactional information about your account.

* **REVOKE CONSENT FOR SEARCH SERVICE AND OTHER SHARING.** If you have signed up for Search Service or otherwise given us permission to share your Personal Information with schools and other organizations, you can opt out at any time by contacting us via email at [**etsinfo@ets.org**](mailto:etsinfo@ets.org).
* **OTHER CHOICES.** You may have the right to object to our use of profiling and/or automated decision that significantly affects you, however, ETS does not use any profiling or automated decision making tools that significantly affect individuals.
* **ACCESS REQUESTS.** You have the right to request a copy of the personal information that ETS maintains about you. To exercise this right, please email [**etsinfo@ets.org**](mailto:etsinfo@ets.org). We will provide you with access to your information as required by law. In some cases, we may need to contact you to verify your identity.
* **CORRECTION REQUESTS.** You have the right to request that we update or correct your personal information. If you have an online account, you can log into your account at any time to access and update the information you have provided to us (with the exception of your name, gender, birthdate or Social Security number, if provided). If you need assistance updating your Personal, please contact us via email at [**etsinfo@ets.org**](mailto:etsinfo@ets.org). We will process your request as required by law. In some cases, we may need to contact you to verify your identity and to obtain evidence for the change. (For example, if you wish to change your name, we will require proof that your name has been changed legally, such as a marriage certificate or court decree.)
* **DELETION REQUESTS.** You have the right to request that we delete or anonymize your personal information. You can also request that we delete your ETS account. To exercise this right, please contact us via email at [**etsinfo@ets.org**](mailto:etsinfo@ets.org). When a request is submitted, you will receive an email to the email address associated with your ETS ID, and you will need to confirm your deletion request. We will process your request as required by law. Please understand that ETS cannot delete personal information in those situations where our retention is required for our internal business purposes or otherwise permitted by law (such as for fraud prevention or legal compliance). _If you no longer have access to the email address associated with your ETS ID, please email us so that we can take other steps to verify your identity._
* **INQUIRIES AND COMPLAINTS.** You have the right to ask us about our privacy practices or to lodge a complaint if you believe that we have violated your privacy rights or failed to properly secure your personal information. To exercise these rights, please email your specific question or concern to [**etsinfo@ets.org**](mailto:etsinfo@ets.org). We take all complaints seriously, and we will do our best to be responsive to your concerns.

### Links to Third-party Sites

Our websites may contain links to other third-party websites for your information and convenience. For example, our websites may contain links to partners that provide test preparation materials (such as Amazon® and EdX®). When you intentionally interact with another company though these links, that company’s own policy will govern the personal information that you provide. These companies are not affiliated with ETS, and ETS does not control the privacy policies or practices of these sites. We suggest you review these company’s privacy policies before providing any information to them. ETS is not responsible for the content or practices of unaffiliated companies, and we provide these links solely for the convenience and information of our visitors.

### Security and Data Retention

ETS has established safeguards to help prevent unauthorized access to or misuse of your Personal Information. These safeguards include physical, technical, organizational and administrative controls.

If you register for an online account with ETS, you will be asked to select a password to help protect your information. These passwords help us verify your identity before granting access or making corrections to any of your Personal Information. You should never disclose your password to anyone. ETS will never ask you for your password in an unsolicited phone call or email. If you believe that your password or your account has been compromised, please contact us as soon as possible.

ETS also has an established records retention program. We retain Personal Information as needed for the purposes listed above and for any additional period of time that may be required by law. Unless the data are being retained in connection with a specific investigation, biometric templates are retained for a maximum of three years.

### Changes to This Privacy Notice

ETS reserves the right to update this Privacy Notice, including to respond to new laws, regulations, or technology, or for other business reasons. Changes will become effective when posted for all Personal Information collected after the date of the change. If the changes will materially affect the way we use or disclose previously collected Personal Information, we will notify you about the change by sending a notice to the primary email address associated with your account.

### International Users and Transfers of Personal Information

ETS, its websites and servers are located in the United States. Therefore, your information, including Personal Information, will be transferred from your location to the United States. It may also be transferred to other countries that provide processing services to ETS at the direction of ETS. However, regardless of where your Personal Information is transferred, we will protect it in accordance with this Privacy Notice.

### How to Contact ETS

If you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Notice or our privacy or security practices, you may contact us by:

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| Email: | [**etsinfo@ets.org**](mailto:etsinfo@ets.org) |
| Mail: | ETS; Rosedale Road; P.O. Box 6666; Princeton, NJ 08541-6666; USA |

### Information About Cookies and Other Data Collection Technologies

When you visit our websites or use our mobile apps, we collect certain information by automated means, using technologies such as cookies, pixel tags, browser analysis tools, server logs and web beacons.

In many cases, the information we collect using cookies and other tools is only used in a non-identifiable way, without any reference to Personal Information. For example, we use information we collect about all website users to optimize our sites and to understand website traffic patterns.

In some cases, we do associate the information we collect using cookies and other technology with your Personal Information. This Privacy Notice governs how we use that information when we associate it with your Personal Information. We do not sell any personal information for monetary consideration. We do share personal information for online targeted advertising, including cross-contextual behavioral advertising, as indicated in the chart in our Privacy Policy. You can opt-out of this sharing at any time by exercising **_Your Privacy Right and Choices_**.

**_We collect personal information and non-personal information using cookies._** A “cookie” is a text file that websites send to a website visitor’s computer or device to uniquely identify the visitor’s web browser and to store information or settings in the browser. You can control cookies by changing your browser’s setting.

Our websites use four kinds of cookies:

* **Strictly necessary cookies**, which are required for our website to operate properly. For example, strictly necessary cookies allow you to put items in your online shopping cart and carry them through checkout. Some strictly necessary cookies are used to help ensure the security of our websites.
* **Functional cookies**, which allow us to recognize your computer when you visit and respect your preferences. For example, these cookies may store your username (if you ask to be remembered).
* **Performance cookies**, which measure how our site works and track usage, such as which pages your visit and how long you spend there. These cookies may be placed by us (or by our service providers) or by our third party advertising partners. We place these cookies to optimize our websites and to improve website performance. Third parties use these cookies to analyze which ads you may have seen.
* **Advertising cookies,** which allow us and our partners to display personalized ads to you on our site and on other websites that you visit. For example, if you look at products on our website, we use advertising cookies to allow our partners to deliver our ads to you for those products on other websites. You may see other companies’ ads on our website delivered by our advertising partners. 

When you visit our websites, we will always place strictly necessary cookies. You have choices about preference, performance and advertising cookies. You can use our Cookie Management Platform to control which of these cookies you wish to accept or to reject all non-necessary cookies. If you exercise your rights to tell us not to sell/share your information to not to use your information for online targeted advertising, we will refrain from placing third party performance cookies and advertising cookies on your browser.

**_Some of our websites may use “Flash” cookies._** Flash cookies (also known as Local Stored Objects) are small data files placed on a computer using Adobe® Flash technology. The Adobe Flash Player is an application that allows rapid development of dynamic content, such as video clips and animation.

We may use Flash cookies to personalize and enhance your online experience and to deliver content for Flash players. We may also use Flash cookies for security purposes, to gather certain website metrics and to help remember settings and preferences. Flash cookies are managed through a different interface than the one provided by your web browser. To manage Flash cookies, please [visit Adobe's website](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html). If you disable Flash cookies or other similar technologies, please be aware that you may not have access to certain content and product features.

**_Our websites use Pixel Tags._** Pixel tags, also known as tracking pixels, web beacons or clear GIFs, are tools used to transmit information to our service providers’ or partner’s servers. When you visit a website or open an email that contains a web beacon, that tool will instruct your browner to transmit information such as your IP address, device details, time of the activity, and nature of the activity (_e.g.,_ email read, web pages visited) to us. These tools allow us to measure response to our communications and to improve our websites. They also enable partners to compile information about your browsing activity on the websites for personalization and online targeted advertising. If you exercise your rights to tell us not to share your information or not to use your information for online targeted advertising, we will refrain from placing pixel tags on your browser.

**_Our websites may use other tracking methods, such as Browser Fingerprinting or Session Recorders._** Our websites use other types of tracking and analytics tools, such as canvas fingerprinting, mouse movement tracking and keystroke analytics. These tools allow us to recognize devices, even if you have rejected cookies, but they are only used for security and fraud detection purposes. For example, we use these tools to detect bots and other threats. We do not sell or share the information collected using these tools, and we do not use this information for online targeted advertising.

**_Our websites collect personal information using Server Logs._** A server log is a text file that records activities on our web services. When you visit a website, we log the date and time of your visit, the device you use to access our website, your operating system type, browser type, domain, and other system settings, as well as the language your system uses and the country and time zone where your device is located. Our server logs also record the IP address of the device you use to connect to the Internet. An IP address is a unique identifier that devices use to identify and communicate with each other on the Internet. We may also collect information about the website you were visiting before you came to ETS and the website you visit after you leave our site. We use this information in aggregate, such as to analyze website traffic patterns and to better understand website user behavior generally. We also use the information for security purposes, to detect threats, and for fraud prevention. For example, we may block login attempts coming from countries where we do not do business. We do not sell or share the information collected by our logs, and we do not use this information for online targeted advertising.

**_Our websites use third party analytics services, such as Google Analytics._** Analytics services help us understand how people use our websites. In some cases, these services are provided by companies that act as service providers for us, meaning that they do not use the information collected for their own purposes. In other cases, the company may combine information collected from users of our websites with information collected from other websites. You have the right to opt-out of having your data combined by these third parties. You can use our Cookie Management Platform to reject all non-necessary cookies. If you exercise your rights to tell us not to sell/share your information to not to use your information for online targeted advertising, we will also refrain from placing third party cookies on your browser.

Additional information about the third party analytics companies that collect data on our websites:

* To learn more and opt out of data collection through Google Analytics:  

**_Our websites integrate with Social Media Platforms._** Our websites may enable you to interact with us and others via social media platforms, such as Facebook, Twitter, YouTube, LinkedIn and Instagram. We may also allow you to login to our websites using social media platform credentials. While we respect each social media platform’s privacy policies, we may collect personal information about you and your friends if you choose to use these tools. If you engage with our content on or through a social media site, you may allow us to have access to certain information associated with your social media account (e.g., name, username, email address, profile picture).

Additionally, social media platforms collect persistent identifiers through your browser or mobile operating system, so they may collect information about your use of our websites. If you have previously provided personally identifiable information to these platforms, the platform operators may recognize you here. Your use of social network plugins is subject to each social media site’s privacy policy. For more information, please read the privacy policies posted by the social media platforms that you use.

We may also display interest-based ads to you when you are using social media platforms. These platforms allow us to personalize the ads that we display to you. We may convert your email address into a unique number which can be matched by the platform with its user to allow delivery of the advertising. You can opt-out of online targeted advertising by exercising **_Your Privacy Rights and Choices_.**

### Information for Job Applicants and ETS Staff

If you are a prospective, current, or former ETS employee or contractor, your personal information is used for customary human resources purposes. You can contact us at [**etsinfo@ets.org**](mailto:etsinfo@ets.org) for more information about our HR Privacy Program.

### Special Notice to California Residents

**The California Consumer Privacy Act (or "CCPA")** provides California residents with specific privacy rights, including the right to receive a privacy notice and to tell companies not to sell your Personal Information.

As a nonprofit, ETS is not directly subject to the CCPA. However, we are deeply committed to protecting the privacy and security of all the Personal Information that is entrusted to us. We do not sell Personal Information.

We have a global privacy program that protects your Personal Information no matter how or where it is collected, used or stored. We also comply with the privacy and security laws that are applicable to us. Our [**Privacy and Security Statement**](https://www.ets.org/content/ets-org/language-master/en/home/legal/privacy.html) describes our privacy and security practices in detail.

If you have any questions or concerns about your privacy, please email us at [**etsinfo@ets.org**](mailto:etsinfo@ets.org).

### Special Notice to Residents in the European Economic Area, Switzerland and the U.K.

ETS is providing this supplemental privacy notice to give individuals in the European Economic Area (EEA) the additional information required by the EU General Data Protection Regulation. These provisions, together with the statements in the ETS Privacy Notice, explain our practices with regard to EEA personal data. These statements also apply to personal data collected in Switzerland and the United Kingdom.

#### **_Information About ETS_**

This notice is being given by ETS in the United States, for itself, its EU Representative (ETS Global B.V.) and its other **EEA affiliates**.

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| U.S. Mail: | ETS; 660 Rosedale Road; Princeton, NJ 08541; USA |
| EU Mail: | ETS Global B.V.; Academic & Business Assessments; Strawinskylaan 929; 1077 XX Amsterdam – The Netherlands |
| Email: | [**etsinfo@ets.org**](mailto:etsinfo@ets.org) |

**The Purposes and Legal Basis for Processing, Including Legitimate Interests**

The Privacy Notice explains the reasons why we process your Personal Information. We only process Personal Information when we have a legal basis for the processing, such as:

* To fulfill a contract with you, such as to provide you with an ETS test or a test offered by another company through ETS.
* For closely related purposes, such as payment processing and financial account management, contract management, website administration, business continuity and disaster recovery, security and fraud prevention, corporate governance, reporting and legal compliance.
* With your consent (or provided you have not objected, as may be applicable), such as to provide you with marketing communications or to send your scores to your designated recipients.

We may also process your Personal Information for the purposes of our legitimate interests, provided that such processing shall not outweigh your rights and freedoms. In particular, we may process your Personal Information as needed to:

* Protect you, us or others from threats (such as security threats or test fraud)
* Improve ETS' tests and support ETS Research initiatives
* Comply with the laws that are applicable to us around the world
* Enable or administer our business, such as for quality control, consolidated reporting and customer service
* Manage corporate transactions, such as mergers or acquisitions
* Understand and improve our business, improve test integrity and for research purposes

**Automated Decision Making and Profiling**

ETS may use automated processes in connection with scoring tests and for similar purposes as needed to provide the test services that you have requested. All such decisions are subject to human review. We will not make automated decisions about you that may significantly affect you, unless (1) the decision is necessary as part of a contract that we have with you, (2) we have your explicit consent, or (3) we are required by law to use the technology. You can learn more about test scoring by reading the information posted about each of our tests.

In some cases, we use certain elements of personal data for ETS Research. For example, we may consider how certain types of test takers (such as nonnative English speakers) respond to specific test questions. Our research initiatives reflect our commitment to fairness and equity in testing, helping to ensure that our tests are accessible and free from bias. They also seek to improve teaching, learning and assessment. Our research results do not contain any identifiable data and are not used to target or profile individuals. Learn more about [**ETS Research**](https://www.ets.org/content/ets-org/language-master/en/home/research.html).

**When You Are Required to Provide Personal Information to ETS**

In most cases, you are not required by law to provide any Personal Information to ETS. You are required to provide certain Personal Information to enable us to enter into a contract with you so that you can use our products and services. Our registration forms indicate which data elements are required for our contracts. If you do not provide these data elements, we cannot do business with you.

If you request an accommodation from ETS, such as special testing conditions needed because of a health condition or disability, you may be required to submit additional Personal Information (including special categories of data) as needed for us to evaluate and respond to your request.

**Your Rights**

As stated in the Privacy Notice, you always have the right to object to our marketing communications. To opt out of emails, simply click the link labeled "Unsubscribe" at the bottom of any email we send you. To revoke permissions that you may have given to send text messages, text STOP in response to any message.

ETS also respects the rights of EEA, Swiss and U.K. residents to access, correct and request erasure or restriction of their personal information as required by law. This means:

* You generally have a right to know whether or not ETS maintains your Personal Information. If we do have your Personal Information, we will provide you with a copy (subject to the rights of others). If your information is incorrect or incomplete, you have the right to ask us to update it.
* You have the right to object to our processing of your Personal Information.
* You may also ask us to delete or restrict your Personal Information.

To exercise these rights, please see **_Your Privacy Rights and Choices_** Please understand that we may need to verify your identify before we can process your request. Additionally, our ability to delete Personal Information will be limited in those cases where we are required to retain records, such as in connection with score reports and test security processes.

If you believe that we have processed your Personal Information in violation of applicable law, you may file a complaint with the ETS Office of the General Counsel or with a supervisory authority.

**International Transfers**

As stated in the Privacy Notice, your Personal Information may be transferred to, stored at or processed in the United States and other countries which may not have equivalent privacy or data protection laws.

We generally use approved Standard Contractual Clauses to assure that Personal Information is adequately protected when it is transferred out of the EEA, U.K. or Switzerland, but we may also make transfers to recipients in places that have been declared adequate, with approved Binding Corporate Rules or pursuant to another derogation.

Please contact us via email at [**etsinfo@ets.org**](mailto:etsinfo@ets.org) if you would like more information about cross-border transfers or to obtain a copy of the Standard Contractual Clauses.

**Data Retention**

We will retain your Personal Information for as long as the information is needed for the purposes set forth above and for any additional period that may be required or permitted by law. If you would like us to delete your personal information, please see **_Your Privacy Rights and Choices_** for information about how to submit a deletion request. Unless we are required by law or have a legitimate interest to retain your information, we will delete it within 30 days of your request.

**How to Contact Us**

Please contact us if you have any questions or comments about our privacy practices or this Privacy Notice. You can always reach us via email at [**etsinfo@ets.org**](mailto:etsinfo@ets.org). You can also reach us via mail at the addresses given above.

Country-specific Privacy Notices/Translations

Australia Brazil Canada China Hong Kong Singapore

See also:
---------

Last Updated on January 19, 2024.

Sign up for ETS updates
-----------------------

Stay up to date with the latest news, announcements and articles

Sign up for updates

Dialog box is opened

ETS Updates

To ensure we provide you with the most relevant content, please tell us a little more about yourself. Your choice helps us customize our communications to fit your needs.

I AM A TEST TAKER or I REPRESENT AN ORGANIZATION OR INSTITUTION

Thank you for subscribing!

Close
